Guide to the Mary Lou Williams Center for Black Culture Records, 1983-1998.
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Mary Lou Williams Center for Black Culture records 1983-1998.
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. Mary Lou Williams Center.
0.7 Linear Feet 750 Items
The Mary Lou Williams Center for Black Culture was established in 1983 to share information about Africana and African-American culture with both the Duke and Durham communities.
The collection contains newspaper clippings, photos, event flyers, Board of Directors information including agendas, minutes, and planning info, material documenting the Center's origins and other printed material relating to its programming and activities.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The Mary Lou Williams Center for Black Culture Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1997-1998.
Historical Note
The Mary Lou Williams Center for Black Culture (MLWC) was established in 1983 to share information about Africana and African-American culture with both the Duke and Durham communities. It is named for the jazz pianist and composer Mary Lou Williams who was a Duke Artist-in-Residence from 1977 until her death in 1981. The Mary Lou Williams Center (as described on its website) seeks to:
"… promote racial understanding, build community, and foster an appreciation for and increase knowledge of Black people, Black history, Black culture, and the vast contributions of people of the African Diaspora. We provide programs and services which contribute to the successful academic and personal development of Black students at Duke University and positively impact the lives of all those whom they encounter. We seek to be a hub for information and activity related to Black students, alumni, and other Black members of the Duke community. We welcome all who seek to engage with and be empowered by a greater understanding of Black experience."
Collection Overview
The collection contains newspaper clippings, photos, event flyers, Board of Directors information including agendas, minutes, and planning info, material documenting the Center's origins and other printed material relating to its programming and activities.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Mary Lou Williams Center for Black Culture
African American college students -- North Carolina -- Durham.
African Americans -- Education (Higher)--North Carolina -- Durham
Williams, Mary Lou, 1910-1981
Color photographs
Related Material
Black Student Alliance records, 1969-2006.
University Archives, Duke University.
Black History at Duke Reference Collection, 1948 - 2001 and undated.
University Archives, Duke University.
University Archives Photograph Collection, 1861-ongoing.
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Mary Lou Williams Center for Black Culture Records, 1983-1998., 1 Box
  - Planning and Organizing Information (Box 1)
  - Board of Directors, Minutes and Agendas, 1983-1987
  - Board of Directors, 1984-1985 (2 folders)
  - Correspondence, Edward Hill, 1984-1995 (2 folders)
  - Invitations and Programs for MLWC Opening, 1983
  - Event Flyers, 1984-1994
  - Event Flyers, 1997-1998
  - Articles, 1979-1994
  - Photos
  - Miscellaneous